克林特
伊斯特伍德
荒野大镖客
又是你 给我滚出去！
You? You again! Get out!
按我说的去做 滚出去！
Do what I told you. Get out!
快跑！看老子怎么教训你
Go on! Run! I'll teach you to keep away from me!
快滚！
Run!
爸爸！
Papa!
你这狗杂种！
You filthy dog!
拿钱来赎你老婆啊
You'll settle with me!
我们走
Let's go.
「再见了 老兄」
欢迎你 陌生人
Welcome to you, stranger.
我叫胡安·迪欧斯 是个撞钟人
My name is Juan de Dios. I am the bell ringer.
你来此贵干？见罗霍家族吗？
Why are you here? To see the Rojos?
不是罗霍家族的话 难道是巴克斯特家族？
No, not the Rojos. Is it the Baxters maybe?
甚至也不是巴克斯特家族
Maybe not even the Baxters.
你想发财 是吗？
You want to get rich, eh?
你若肯用脑
Well, for that you have come to the right place...
那可就来对了地方了
If you use your head.
因为这里的人要么发达
That's because everybody here has become very rich...
要么死掉
or else they are dead.
你想买什么？枪？酒？
What do you want to buy? Some guns? Liquor?
你不是买家 是卖家 卖线索来换黄金
You don't buy. You sell. You sell lead in exchange for gold.
在这里你要么发达 要么死掉
You will get rich here, or you'll be killed.
看来我又要敲丧钟了
Juan de Dios tolls the bell once again.
你好啊 这位朋友
Saludos, amigo!
离家漂泊可不明智啊
It's not smart to go wandering so far from home.
我想他是选错路了
I reckon he picked the wrong trail.
或是选错了地方
Or he could have picked the wrong town.
我想 他最大的错是投错了胎
His big mistake, I think, was getting born.
你如果想找工作  而又穿成这样
If you want any work, lookin' like that...
可以试试当稻草人
you could try bein' a scarecrow.
得了吧 乌鸦都可以把他吓尿
Oh, no, the crows are liable to scare him maybe.
你好
Hello.
Saludos.
你这样是不会发达的
You can't get rich like that.
顶多 你会被人干掉
At most, you will only succeed in being killed.
看看我们这里的麻烦 我们只能靠你了
With all of the trouble we have, all we needed was you.
-要点什么？-食物和喝的东西
-What are you looking for?  -Food and something to drink.
-水在那边  -不 不要水
-Water's over there. -No, no water.
吃饱喝足 然后杀人
Eating and drinking and killing.
你的能耐仅此而已 你们这种人都一样
That's all you can do, just like the rest of your kind.
对了 我要赊账
By the way, you'll have to mark this up.
我知道 你没有钱
I know. You have no money.
毕竟 你刚到镇上
After all, you just got into town.
但你若不在乎杀人的话
But if you don't mind doing a little killing...
会有很多人乐意付钱请你的
You will have no trouble finding someone eager to pay you.
就连我的轮盘赌也被卖掉了
My roulette wheel. That, too, was murdered.
没人来这里玩了
No one ever comes here to play.
我们这的人把时间都花在丧葬上了
We spend our time here between funerals and burials.
从没见过这么死气沉沉的小镇
Never saw a town as dead as this one.
你永远找不出第二个这样的小镇
You will never see another like it.
-这里到底怎么了？-这里充斥太多杀戮
-What's wrong with the place?  -We've had too many killings.
看到那些女人了吗？
You have seen the women?
她们不是女人 是寡妇
None of them are women. They're widows.
这个地方只有寡妇
The place is only widows.
在这里 只有杀人才能得到尊敬
Here you can only gain respect by killing other men.
所以再也没人工作了
So nobody works anymore.
看来有人不同意你的观点
Seems somebody doesn't share your opinion.
是嘛
Yes.
你好
Saludos.
知道皮里佩洛为什么会看你吗？
Know why Piripero looked you over?
是在量你的尺寸
To take your measurements.
他经验丰富 只看一眼就够了
He is so experienced. he can do it with a glance.
你会光顾他的
You will be a customer.
别笑 我不是在说笑
Don't laugh. I'm not joking.
我警告你 那些歹徒总有一天会干掉你
I want to warn you that those murderers will make a corpse out of you one day.
所以我想让你离开这里
That's why I want you to get out of here.
你不想呆在墓地里吧
You don't want to stay in this cemetery.
吃完就离开吧
Finish up and get out.
我跟你说过我没钱
I told ya I can't pay ya.
算我请客
Be my guest...
离开圣米格尔 好吗？
but get out of San Miguel, will you?
这通向哪里？
Where does that lead?
阳台
The balcony.
你去上面干什么？喂
Why are you going there? Hey!
就看看
To have a look.
在高处俯瞰 总会有不同的发现
Things always look different from higher up.
但是上面什么都没有
But nothing's up there.
快点离开吧！
Go ahead and get out!
他们是谁？
Who are they?
强盗 强盗和走私犯
Bandits. Bandits and smugglers.
他们从德克萨斯来的
They come down from Texas.
他们穿越边境来囤积枪和酒
They cross the frontier to stock up on guns and liquor.
这里的成本比较低
The cost is much less here.
然后他们回去把枪和酒卖给印第安人
Then they go back and sell the guns and liquor to the Indians.
每个卖枪和酒的城镇都会致富
Any town that sells guns and liquor has gotta be a rich one.
不是城镇致富 是买主卖主致富
Not the town, only those who buy and sell...
那些老大才是挣巨额利润的人
and the bosses are the ones who clean up.
是吗？总得有人掌管这里 每个城镇都有个老大
Yeah? Somebody has to run the place. Every town has a boss.
没错 但当这个城镇有两个老大的话...
That's true, but when there are two around...
一山不容二虎
then I'd say that there is one too many.
两个老大
Two bosses?
有意思
Very interesting.
确实有意思
Interesting is right.
这边是罗霍家族 三兄弟兜售烈酒
The Rojos boys, three brothers who sell liquor.
那边是巴克斯特家族 大军火贩
And then there's the Baxters, big gun merchants.
我没搞错的话  你已跟巴克斯特的人碰过面了吧？
If I'm not mistaken, you already met Baxter's gang, didn't you?
嗯 见过了
Yeah, we met.
你真走运 他们很少只对骡子开火
But you're lucky. They don't usually limit their fire to the mule.
每当一个男人背井离乡 来此处转悠
A man leaves his own land and looks around for any reason...
胡安·迪欧斯就会敲一下钟 皮里佩洛就会多卖一副棺材
Juan de Dios tolls the bell and Piripero sells another coffin.
两个老大
Two bosses.
他们招募边境两边所有无所事事的人渣
They've enlisted all the scum that hangs around both sides of the frontier...
以美元支付酬劳
and they pay in dollars.
巴克斯特家族在那边
The Baxters over there.
罗霍家族在那边
The Rojos there.
我就在中间
Me right in the middle.
你想干什么？
Where you do what?
敲钟的疯子是对的
Crazy bell ringer was right.
这是个可以发财的好地方
There's money to be made in a place like this.
如果我猜对你想干的事 我劝你还是别尝试
If you're thinking what I suspect, I tell you, don't try it.
他们两边谁比较厉害？
Which one of the two is the stronger?
他们两边谁厉害？
Which one of them is stronger?
罗霍家族 尤其是雷蒙
Well, the Rojos, especially Ramon.
米格尔·罗霍阁下 我想跟你谈谈
Don Miguel Rojo, I want to talk to you.
米格尔阁下 我听说你在招募成员
Don Miguel, I hear you're hiring on men.
我可能很适合
Well, I might just be available.
在你雇佣我之前 我想告诉你
I gotta tell you before you hire me...
我要价可不便宜
I don't work cheap.
准备三副棺材吧
Get three coffins ready.
再见了 老兄
Adios, amigo.
听着 异乡人 你还不明白吗？
Listen, stranger! Didn't you get the idea?
我们不想在镇里看到你这种人
We don't like to see bad boys like you in town.
快找你的骡子滚吧
Go get your mule.
你让它跑了吗？
You let him get away from you?
我正想跟你们谈这事
That's what I want to talk to you about.
-它现在心情低落  -谁？
-He's feeling real bad. -Hmm?
我的骡子
My mule.
你们开枪射它的蹄子 使它受了惊
He got all riled up when you men fired those shots at his feet.
喂 你在说笑吗？
Hey, are you makin' some kind of joke?
没有
Eh, No.
我知道你们只是玩玩而已
I understand you men were just playin' around.
但是骡子...它不了解
But the mule... He just doesn't get it.
当然 如果你们道歉的话
Of course, if you were to all apologize.
还笑 我觉得这样很差劲
I don't think it's nice, you laughin'.
我的骡子不喜欢别人笑它
My mule don't like people laughin'.
一旦笑它 它就会发狂
He gets the crazy idea you're laughin' at him.
但你们若肯道歉  我知道你们会的...
Now, if you apologize, like I know you're going to...
我会说服它 你们不是故意的
I might convince him that you really didn't mean it.
我都看到了 你把他们四个都杀了
I saw the whole thing. You killed all four of them.
你会付出代价 会被绞死的
You'll pay all right. You'll be strung up.
你是谁？
Who are you?
别开枪
Don't fire a shot.
我叫约翰·巴克斯特 是警长
I'm John Baxter, sheriff.
是吗？你是警长的话
Yeah? Well, if you're the sheriff,
最好把这些人埋了
you better get these men underground.
我错了 应该是四副棺材
My mistake. Four coffins.
我告诉过你我要价不便宜
I told you I wasn't cheap...
但你会发觉是物有所值的
but I think you'll find it's worth your while.
97 98 99 100
97, 98, 99, 100.
剩下的等成事后再给
The rest when you're all done.
我什么时候开始？
When do I start?
至少现在我还不急
I'm not in a hurry, at least for the moment.
巴克斯特少了四个成员 现在正是大好时机
I'd say with four less Baxters, right now is as good a time to start as any.
我听说几天后 有一队骑兵会经过这里
In a few days I hear there will be a troop of cavalry passing through here.
我不希望军队插手我们的生意
I wouldn't want the military sticking their long noses into our business.
看来你的消息很灵通
You seem to be well informed.
在这种地方 要活命就得靠小道消息
In these parts, a man's life often depends on a mere scrap of information.
这玩意儿对使用者来说派不上什么用场
This thing couldn't have been very useful to its owner.
我弟弟雷蒙做的 他经常拿它做射击训练
My brother Ramon did that. He often uses it for target practice.
只要他手中有枪 就无人敢挡
With a gun in his head, no one stands in his way.
这副盔甲是他最喜欢的靶子之一
The suit of armor is one of his favorite targets...
当然 是当他没别的东西可射击时才用
Naturally when he does not have anything better to shoot.
我还真有点想会会你这位弟弟了
Well, I'll be kind of curious to meet this brother of yours.
这位是奇科 我最信任的手下之一
This is Chico, one of the most trusted of my men.
跟他走 他会带你去你的房间
Follow him. He will bring you to your room.
希望你有回到自己家的感觉
I would like you to feel at home.
我从没有自己家 不过还是走吧
Well, I never found home that great, but let's go.
她是谁？
Who's that?
她叫玛丽索尔 你最好别打她主意
Her name's Marisol. You just forget about her.
这是你的房间
This one will be your room.
你给了他100美元
You gave him $100.
我们从没付过这么多钱
We never pay that much.
你能解释你为什么要雇用他吗？
Can you explain to me why you have taken him on?
让那个恶心的美国佬白吃白住 还给他100美元？
To have that filthy gringo around the house and to give him $100 besides?
我们从来没给过那么高的价钱
We have never paid anybody so much
你不能让那种人在这里为所欲为
You cannot leave someone like that to do what he wants around here.
他什么事都做得出来
He's capable of doing anything.
而我只想要这里井然有序
And I want law and order in this place.
如果你只要这些  那我有更便宜的办法
If that is all you want, there is a much cheaper way.
做了他
Just snuff him out.
谁来动手呢？你吗？
And who would be the one? You?
有何不可？
Yes, why not?
朝他背后开一枪就能解决所有麻烦
A shot in his back, then you would have him out of the way in no time at all.
听着 我现在可以轻易得手
Listen, I could do it easily right now.
他无法预料 我还可以取回那一百元
He won't be expecting it, and I'd get back the hundred.
你真蠢 伊斯特班 即便是兄弟我也敢骂你
You are stupid, Esteban! Even if you are my brother!
背后放冷枪就解决问题？
A bullet in the back, eh? And it is ended!
那万一你手抖射偏了呢？
And what happens if your hand should tremble slightly?
万一他只是受了点伤呢？
And he's only hurt?
骑兵队就要来了 那美国佬拔枪又特别快
And with the cavalry arriving in town and that Yankee so quick on the draw.
-我只是想...  -你别瞎想了
-I was only thinking... -You mustn't think of anything!
让我来做主
You let me do the thinking instead.
去看看那个美国佬 问他需要些什么 跟他交个朋友
Go and see the americano. Just ask him if he needs anything and make friends.
你给我听清楚
Get one thing clear in that head of yours.
在雷蒙回来之前 镇上不能节外生枝
This is going to be a quiet town until Ramon gets back!
明白吗？不能节外生枝
Is that clear? A quiet town.
我是伊斯特班·罗霍 我哥哥叫我...
I am Esteban Rojo. My brother asked me to...
你在做什么呢？
What are you doing?
搬走
Moving.
你难道不知道所有手下得跟我们一起住吗？
But didn't you know all our men live here with us?
是很舒适 但我发现你们并不是都很欢迎我
That's all very cozy, but I don't find you men all that appealin'.
再说了 你哥哥说现在用不着我
Besides, your brother said he didn't have any need for me anymore right now.
立定
Halt!
-军士？-什么事 长官？
-Sergeant. -Yes, sir.
传令今晚我们驻扎此地
Tell the men we'll be spending tonight here in this place.
安排他们来这里领取补给
Arrange it so they can pick up the supplies here.
还有 加倍守卫 看好马车
Also, double the guard in order to watch the stagecoach there.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
你猜那马车上装着什么？
What do you suppose they're carrying in that coach?
很容易查明
It'd be easy to find out.
走近看清楚就行了
Get up close to it and take a little look at what's in it.
如果他们向你开枪 那么里面就是金子
If they fire at you, you know it's gold.
这主意不赖啊
Not a bad idea.
在找什么？
Looking for anything?
你好
Hello.
走开 美国佬
Get out of here, Yankee.
你怎么没睡呢？
Why aren't you sleeping?
看到你这样瞪着 我很不安
When I see you staring like that, it bothers me.
我还在想那马车里有什么
I still keep wondering what was in that stagecoach.
一定是他们认为很重要的东西
It's something they seem to think is very important.
我随口问了几个问题  队长差点要抓我
I asked a few questions of the captain and almost was arrested.
玛丽索尔是什么人？
Who's Marisol?
你最好睡会儿 你会需要的
You better get some sleep. You need it.
就算是你 也太危险了
It's much too dangerous, even for you.
我只是问她是谁
All I did is ask who she was.
一个女人
She is a woman.
雷蒙爱她爱疯了
And Ramon's madly in love with her.
现在明白了吧？
Does that make it clear to you?
镇里的每个人都谈论雷蒙
Everybody in this town talks about Ramon.
真想会会他
Kind of curious to meet him.
如果你够聪明的话
If you are smart, you will try to stay
就尽可能远离雷蒙
clear of Ramon as long as possible.
那些军人正悄悄地前进
There are the soldiers. They are moving on very quietly.
好奇怪
Strange.
他们是往边境前进
They're headed for the frontier.
告诉我
Tell me...
你每晚都是这样睡觉的吗？
is that the way you go to bed every night?
别担心 我不会弄脏被单的
Don't worry. I didn't dirty the sheets.
等等 我也去
Wait. I'm coming too.
我要看看你是怎样惹祸上身的
I want to see for myself how you're going to get yourself in trouble.
好了好了 走吧
All right. All right. Go ahead.
就像玩老鹰捉小鸡一样
It's like playing cowboys and Indians.
-上尉  -欢迎 中尉
-Captain. -Welcome, Lieutenant.
这是答应给你的黄金
There's your gold as promised.
希望你给我们的枪械 对军队一样有用
I hope the guns you will be giving us will be equally useful to our army.
请放心 上尉 我们一起验货
Rest assured, Captain. We'll check them over together.
快给他们换上衣服
Get their clothes on again, and hurry.
务必把尸首安置好
Be sure to place them around right.
别忘了 他们是互相残杀的
Remember. They died fighting among themselves.
卢比奥！
Rubio!
看到没 他就是雷蒙
There. It's Ramon.
这是我的弟弟雷蒙
This is my brother Ramon.
我想我提过他了
I think I mentioned him.
人人都在谈雷蒙
Everybody talks about Ramon.
也有很多人提到你 包括我亲爱的兄长
And many speak of you, too, my dear brother included.
希望他们说的是好话
Well, I hope they say nice things.
旅程愉快吗？
Did you have a good trip?
很累
It was tiring.
大白天赶路酷热难耐
It was terribly hot on the road during the day.
坐马车也不舒服
And stagecoaches are an uncomfortable way to travel.
我肯定你很快就恢复了
Well, I'm sure you'll be in great shape in no time.
美国佬等不及要行动了
The americano cannot wait to get into action.
抱歉 恐怕要让他失望了
I am sorry. He's going to be a disappointed man.
为什么
How's that?
巴克斯特接受了邀请 他们今晚赴约 米格尔阁下
The Baxters accepted the invitation. They'll come tonight, Don Miguel.
巴克斯特来这里？你疯了吧
The Baxters coming here? You must be out of your head.
是我吩咐奇科邀请他们的 他听从我的命令
Chico followed my orders. I told him to invite them here.
雷蒙 这是怎么回事？
Ramon, what is this?
在旅途之中我领悟了很多事
I have found out many things when I was traveling...
我们两边这样火拼下去 没完没了
and I have decided that it's very stupid...
是非常愚蠢的
to just keep on shooting at each other and without any results.
你疯了 雷蒙
You've gone out of your mind, Ramon.
不 我很理智 伊斯特班
No, I have come to my senses, Esteban.
相信我
Believe me.
Trust me.
生命很宝贵
Life can be so precious.
浪费每一分钟都很愚蠢 不是吗？
It's foolish to risk losing it every minute, no?
这个镇子很大 足以容纳每个人
There's plenty of space for everybody in this town.
包括巴克斯特家族
Even Baxters, hmm?
因此...
For this reason...
我决定放下武器
I've decided to hang my gun up on the wall.
我觉得雷蒙说得对
I think that Ramon has the right idea.
我也厌倦了打打杀杀 是时候停战了
I, too, am getting tired of these killings. They must stop.
这些话让人非常感动
This is all very, very touching.
你是说你不赞赏和平？
You mean you don't admire peace?
让一个人去喜欢他不了解之事 是很难的
It's not real easy to like something you know nothing about.
呆在圣米格尔 你会学到很多东西的
Stay in San Miguel and you may just profit from the experience.
不了 谢谢 我要走
No, thanks. I'll be movin' on.
这是你的钱 米格尔阁下
Here's your money, Don Miguel.
我只花了一点儿
I only used a small amount of it.
我无功不受禄
I don't like to take money unless I feel I've earned it.
你干嘛急着走？你应该呆在这里
Now, why are you so hasty? You should stay here.
你可以和我们共享晚餐
You might enjoy dining with us tonight.
因为我 巴克斯特失去四个手下
The Baxters have four men in the cemetery on account of me.
我想他们不希望我在场
I don't think they'd appreciate my presence.
我不喜欢那个美国佬 作为雇佣枪手 他聪明过头了
I don't like that americano. He's too smart to be just a hired fighter.
-但他枪法无人能比  -我看得出来
-At shooting a gun no one can touch him. -I can see that.
这样一副嘴脸的人以枪谋生 你可以料到两件事情
When someone with that face works with his gun, you may count on two things.
他枪法神速 机智过人
He's fast on the trigger, but he's also intelligent.
这种人太危险了 兄弟们
That makes him too dangerous for you, I think, my brothers.
既然他走了 你能解释一下那番白痴言论吗
Now that he's gone, will you please explain that silly nonsense...
什么放下武器 和巴克斯特家族和解？
about hanging up your gun and making up with the Baxters?
老兄 有没有可能
Is it possible, old fellow...
你永远无法自己得出任何结论？
that you'll never be able to reach any conclusions on your own?
你难道认为政府和美国佬一旦发现尸体后
Don't you think our government and the americanos will find those bodies...
不会展开调查吗？
and then start an investigation?
就让他们调查
They'll investigate, all right...
我们暂且沉寂 和平地度过这段时间
and we'll be quiet and peacefully abide our time.
我们对于里奥·布拉沃的大屠杀一无所知 是吧？
We know nothing about the massacre at the Rio Bravo, eh?
我故意把尸体排列成
I arranged for the bodies to be lying...
自相残杀而亡
as if both companies killed each other.
但你认为他们会相信吗？
But do you think they'll believe it?
我认为他们会
Yes, I think so.
因为若他们找不到凶手...
Because if they don't find some guilty party...
就自然会放弃调查
It would be a pretty good reason to call off the investigation.
没错 那巴克斯特家族呢？
Yes, but what about the Baxters?
巴克斯特家族？
The Baxters?
他们就想着和平共处
They want nothing more than to live in peace.
我们暂时让他们为所欲为
We'll let them have their own way for a while.
别管巴克斯特家族了
Forget about the Baxters.
调查结束之后我们再好好招待他们
We'll take care of them later when the investigation finishes.
你那个主意真不错
That was a fine idea that you had.
是什么来着？
What was it again?
是了 是了
Ah, yes, yes, yes.
巴克斯特家族在这边 罗霍家族在那边
The Baxters are on one side. The Rojos on the other.
你就在中间
And you'd be in the middle.
问题是他们结盟了
The only problem is that they've joined up.
现在你找不到工作了
Now you are without a job,
也没有钱付你的帐了
and you don't have money to pay me what you owe me.
你现在只有一个选择 赶紧离开这里
There is only one thing for you to do. Leave here immediately.
我可以不计较你欠的钱
I will forget about what you owe me.
离开圣米格尔 再也别回来了
You leave San Miguel and never come back for the rest of your days.
乔 我已经照你要求弄好马车了
Eh, Joe, I have prepared the wagon the way you asked me to.
后座有两副空棺
It's sitting out in the back here with two empty coffins.
你做好决定了吗？
What are you up to?
要转行吗？
Are you changing your profession?
如果你想谋生的话 最好转行
If you want to go on living, you'd better.
我认为你会是个很好的抬棺人
In my opinion, you'll make a fine pallbearer.
关了这家店 跟我一起走 好吗？
Close this place and come with me, huh?
关店？好吧 我们去哪里呢？
Oh, close up, huh? It's done. Where are we going?
我想知道我们要去哪里 这要保密吗？
I'd like to know where we are going, or is it a secret?
去河边看一下那里的尸体
Down by the river. Have a look at some corpses down there.
罗霍家族发出邀请 我们必须赴宴
The Rojos say come to dinner and we must go.
但我根本不想去
But I don't like it at all...
即使他们答应了我们的种种要求
even if they've granted all the guarantees we've demanded.
我们还是要去 但别碰任何东西
We'll go along with it, but don't touch anything.
你们不能吃 不能喝
You mustn't eat. You mustn't drink.
擦亮眼睛 保持警惕
You just keep your eyes open and keep your wits about you.
你确定没有人看到我们？
Are you sure that nobody has seen us?
也许一两个鬼看见了
Only a ghost or two.
呸呸呸 别拿鬼来开玩笑
Oh no no no. Don't joke about things like this.
最好是别招惹亡魂
Ghosts are better left where they are.
你看起来很适合这块地方
You look as though this place suits you very well.
如果你再这样下去 你很快就会长眠于此
If you go on like this, you will soon be here permanently.
我不明白
I do not understand.
为什么河岸有那么多尸体
Why is it with all those bodies down
你只埋这两具？
by the river we are just burying these two?
我们不是要埋葬他们
We're not. We're not gonna bury them.
你这话是什么意思？
What do you mean we're not burying them?
没错 我们不是要埋葬他们
That's right. We're not gonna bury them.
如果不埋葬他们 那我们用这些尸体干嘛？
If we are not going to bury them, what will we use them for?
为什么要这么大费周章？
Why are we taking the trouble to do this?
死人有时很有用
The dead can be very useful sometimes.
他们不止一次帮我度过难关
They've helped me out of tough spots more than once.
首先 死人不会说话
First, they don't talk.
其次 如果我弄好了 他们看起来会像活人
Second, they can be made to look alive if I manage it right.
还有...
And, third...
如果你向他们开枪 不必担心
Well, third, if you shot them, there's no worry,
因为他们已经死透了
'cause they're dead already.
明白了吗？
Understand?
我什么都不明白 我要走了
It doesn't make a bit of sense to me, and I'm getting out.
我还活着 就要跟活人呆一起 懂吗？
I'm alive, and I want to remain with the living, understand?
等我死了 再跟死人呆一起吧
And when I'm dead, I'll want to remain with the dead.
强迫我与活人呆一起 我会不高兴的
I would be unhappy if somebody living forces me to remain with the living.
我说清楚了吧
I hope that's clear.
还有 我也不喜欢你这样摆布尸体
And, also, I don't like the idea that you've placed those bodies there!
葬在那里的人是这个不幸的小镇上  唯一死于肺炎的人
The man buried there is the only one who died of pneumonia in this cursed town!
冷静点 好吗？
Take it easy, will ya?
这两个朋友会帮我付你的帐单
These two friends of ours here are gonna make me pay your bill.
驾
Get up there!
他们唯一能挑起战争的方式是...
The only reason they could have to start a war with us...
把你从我身边绑走
would be to kidnap you from your husband's side.
这个罗霍太英勇了
He's gallant, this Rojo.
我觉得他担不起这样的恭维
I really didn't think him capable of compliments.
并不是 他的所言跟他的提议一样 都是虚伪的
And he's not. All that he says is false, like his proposals.
你们女人 如果事态简单 反而会疑神疑鬼
You women! If things aren't complicated for you, you become suspicious.
没错 因为在我看来就是不太对劲
Yes, because to me, it just didn't seem right.
太顺利了 我不相信他们
It went too smoothly. I don't trust them.
你想证明我错了 是吗？
You'd like to prove me wrong, wouldn't you?
一向如此
Always the same thing.
-晚安  -晚安
-Good night. -Good night.
别怕 我不会伤害你的
Don't worry. I'm not gonna hurt ya.
我只想让你知道
I just want you to know why the
罗霍家族急于和解的原因
Rojos want to make peace all of a sudden.
不久前有一队士兵  用马车载着黄金
You see, there was once a wagon load of gold that the soldiers
运往边境
were taking to the border.
约翰 快上来
John, come up here quickly.
抱歉 但当丈夫在妻子卧室里发现一个男人时
Sorry, but when a husband finds a man in his wife's bedroom...
你永远想不到他会做出什么举动
you're never sure how he's gonna react.
-给他500元  -为什么？
-Give him $500. -How's that?
把钱给他
Give the money to him.
他有条有趣的消息 听他讲
He has an interesting story. Listen to him.
消息可靠吗？你没搞错吧？
That's the right idea? You didn't misunderstand?
-只要我想我才会给出不可靠的消息 -雷蒙
-I get the wrong idea only when it suits me. -Ramon.
-什么事？-护送金子的士兵
-What is it?  -The soldiers the ones who escorting the gold.
有两个逃走了 躲在墓地里
Two of those soldiers got away. They are hiding out in the cemetery.
巴克斯特正要去抓他们
The Baxters. They're about to capture them.
卢比奥 叫弟兄们集合
Rubio, et the men!
你的消息很灵通啊？
You are well informed, eh?
在这种地方 要活命就得靠小道消息
A man's life in these parts often depends on a mere scrap of information.
你哥哥亲口说的
Your brother's own words.
说 你为什么要帮我们？
Tell me. Why are you doing this for us?
为了500元
$500.
要是这两个士兵出面指证雷蒙
With these two soldiers as witnesses against Ramon...
政府就会端掉罗霍家族的势力了
the government will be able to rid the town of the Rojos and their whole band.
到那时圣米格尔只有一个老大
Then San Miguel will have just one boss.
快
Hurry!
我们走
Let's go!
跟我们一起去吗？
Coming with us?
当一个男人口袋里有了钱
When a man's got money in his pocket,
他就开始欣赏和平
he begins to appreciate peace.
快点
Come on!
把马留在这里
Let's leave the horses here.
你怎么看？
What do you think?
不知道
I don't know.
有点不对劲
There's something about it I don't like.
一动不动 不像受伤 倒像假人
Too still to be wounded. More like dummies.
当然 罗霍巴不得是假人
Sure, dummies that are very interesting to the Rojos.
最好藏起来 快点
Better hide. Hurry.
我们该怎么办？
What'll we do?
带两个弟兄绕到两边开火
Take two men and circle around to the side.
尽量和他们周旋 好让我去干掉那两个人
Try to keep them busy long enough for me to get those two down there.
去吧 去吧 快点
Go on. Go on. Quickly.
掩护我 我去解决那两个人
Keep me covered. I am going to take care of those two.
听着 巴克斯特 如果你想要这两人 就带走吧
Listen, Baxter! You can have them now if you like!
因为死人不会说话！
Since dead men can't talk!
看来他们不喜欢我这个玩笑
It seems they didn't like my joke.
再过一会儿就放他们回家
We'll let them go home in a little while.
好好招待这个坏小子...
We will keep this bad boy as our guest...
直到巴克斯特离开圣米格尔 奔向边境
only until Baxter leaves San Miguel and heads for the frontier.
把他关在地窖
Put him in the cellar.
伊斯特班 干得好
Esteban, Good work!
有了安东尼奥这个人质 巴克斯特一定得屈服
With Antonio as our prisoner, the Baxters have to give in to us.
现在我们可以随意开条件了
Now we can make any kind of demand.
米格尔阁下 米格尔阁下
Don Miguel! Don Miguel!
发生什么事了？还能说话吗？
What has happened? Talk, will you?
我不知道 但有人向我开枪
I don't know, but somebody shot at me.
玛丽索尔？
Marisol?
你在哪 玛丽索尔？
Where are you, Marisol?
奇怪 你总是在合适的时间出现在合适的地方
It's strange how you always manage to be in the right place at the right time.
她伤势不严重 头疼会缓解的
It's nothing serious. A headache that will pass.
她要睡觉
She'll sleep.
好好看着 不许让她离开房间半步 听到了吗？
Keep your eyes open. She's not to move from that room. You hear?
我不会跟任何人说是我带她来这里的
I wouldn't mention anything about me bringing her here.
我不想让罗霍认为我站在你们这边
I wouldn't want the Rojos to think I was on your side.
别担心
Don't worry.
我是有钱的女人 我赏识用金钱收买的男人
I'm a woman who's rich enough to appreciate the men my money can buy.
我已经跟罗霍家族谈妥了
I've been to talk to the Rojos.
他们愿意用安东尼奥换玛丽索尔
They'll give back Antonio in exchange for Marisol.
时间定在明天上午
It'll take place in the morning.
你很快就会发财了
Very soon you are going to be rich.
是啊 我可不会为此而心碎
Yeah, and that's not gonna break my heart.
她在哪？你说我可以去见她的
Where is she? You said I'd be able to see her!
她在哪？
Where is she?
我要见她！
I wanna see her!
-回来 耶瑟 过来  -我想见！
-Come back here, Jesus. Come here. -I wanna see!
我想见她 我想见她
I want to see her! I want to see her!
我为什么不能见她呢？我想见她
Why can't I look at her? I want to see her!
去吧 去他那里 玛丽索尔
Go. Go to him, Marisol.
妈妈
Mama!
-妈妈  -耶瑟
-Mama! -Jesus!
胡里奥
Julio.
玛丽索尔
Marisol.
干掉胡里奥
Get Julio.
我们警告过你 离开这个镇
You were warned to get out of town.
现在我要给你做个了断
Now I'm gonna make you pay once and for all.
别动他
Let him be!
你最好快走 雷蒙在等着
You better get goin'. Ramon's waitin'.
还有你 还不快带孩子回家
And, you, get that kid home where he belongs.
雷蒙那个畜生
A pig, that Ramon.
雷蒙和他们有什么关系？
What's Ramon got to do with them?
没人告诉你吗？
You weren't told, eh?
这故事在这里流传很久了
In this part of the world, the story is very old.
原本快乐的小家庭遇上了麻烦
A happy little family until trouble comes along.
而麻烦的名字就叫雷蒙
And trouble has the name of Ramon.
他声称玛丽莎的丈夫在赌博时出老千 根本没这回事
Claiming the husband cheated at cards, which wasn't true...
他把他的妻子抓来做人质 实则是同居
He gets the wife to live with him as hostage.
那丈夫呢？
And the husband?
他？他什么都做不了
Him? There's nothing for him to do.
罗霍威胁说要杀了他的儿子耶瑟...
The Rojos threatened to kill his little boy Jesus...
他只能接受现实
and he was forced to accept things.
那个雷蒙很聪明
That Ramon is smart.
你去哪里？
Where are you going?
向罗霍家族讨份工作
To the Rojos to look for a job.
很高兴美国佬站在我们这边
I am glad we have the americano with us.
对我们来说是最好的结果
It's the best thing that could have happened to us, you know...
因为一旦政府要展开调查
'cause if either government starts an inquiry...
我们需要大量地招兵买马
We'll need every man we can get.
你知道现在跟巴克斯特开战
I guess you know to be at war with the Baxters now...
比坐在一箱炸药上还危险
is worse than sitting on a big case of dynamite.
-这个放哪里？-放在那里
-Where should we put this?  -Put it over there.
来 大家一起干杯！
Come on, everybody! Drink up!
好枪法 真是好枪法
Good shooting. Very good shooting.
想杀人时 一定得瞄准他的心脏
When you want to kill a man, you must shoot for his heart.
而温切斯特是最好的武器
And the Winchester is the best weapon.
挺好 但我还是喜欢我的点45口径手枪
That's very nice, but I'll stick with my a.45.
当手持点45手枪的人  对决手持来福枪的人
When a man with a.45 meets a man with a rifle...
拿手枪的人必死无疑
The man with the pistol will be a dead man.
那是一句墨西哥谚语 说得没错
That's an old Mexican proverb, and it's true.
你相信吗？
You believe that?
帕奎托 派五个弟兄送玛丽索尔回小屋
Paquito, take five men and escort Marisol to the small house.
直到我回去
Stay there till I return.
-一切都准备好了  -不要担心
-Everything's prepared. -Do not be worried.
我明天就回去
I will return tomorrow.
马车都准备好了 我们可以走了
All the wagons are ready. We can leave.
各位 我不在的时候玩尽兴点
Everyone, enjoy yourselves during my absence.
你们都听到雷蒙说的了 尽情享乐吧
You heard Ramon. Let's have a good time.
-他好重  -是的
-He weighs over a ton. -Of course...
他灌了那么多酒
with all he poured into himself.
爸爸
Papa.
你不是说任何人都不准见妈妈吗？
Did you not tell me no one could go see Mama?
是的
That's right.
那为什么我不可以见 那男人却可以呢？
Then why does that man see her when I cannot?
-我要妈妈  -不要站在门口
-I want Mama. -Go away from the door.
我要妈妈
I want Mama.
安静点！
Quiet!
我们不能被人发现
We cannot show ourselves.
你必须记住 不要靠近门口
You must remember that. You must stay away.
大家好
Hello.
有人在小屋那边开枪
There's somebody shooting up at the small house.
立即备马 快去 我们走
Saddle the horses immediately! Come on. Let's go!
小心！
Look out!
给 拿着这些钱
Here you are. Now, take this money.
够你们维持一段生活了 现在 穿过边境
It's enough to live on for a while. Now, get across the border.
离圣米格尔越远越好
Get as much distance between yourselves and San Miguel as possible.
我们该怎么感谢你？
How may we thank you for what you are doing?
不用 在罗霍家族来到之前赶快离开这里
Don't try. Just get goin' before the Rojos get here.
你为什么帮我们呢？
Why do you do this for us?
为什么？因为我曾认识一个跟你很像的人
Why? 'Cause I knew someone like you once.
却无人出手相助 现在 快走吧
There was no one there to help. Now, get movin'.
离开这里
Get movin'.
Get out of here!
怎么了 奇科？
What do you see, Chico?
他们全死了 全被屠杀了
They're all dead. They massacred them.
-他们绑架了玛丽索尔 -看上去是巴克斯特家族下的手
-They kidnapped Marisol! -Looks like the work of the Baxters.
快 要赶在他们袭击我们的大本营前回去
Quick, let's get back before they attack our house and the town.
奇科 你去分发武器
Chico, give out the ammunition.
伊斯特班 在房子周边布置人手 提高警惕
Esteban, spread your men around the house. Keep your eyes open.
米格尔 帕克 文森特 马丁 到后面去
Miguel, Paco, Vincente, Martin, behind the house.
马诺洛和阿瓦罗 跟我来 警惕点
Manolo and Alvaro, come with me. Stay alert.
根据屋内死者的情况看来 他们一定人多势众
The way they killed the men in the small house, there must be a lot of them.
这是个和煦的夜晚
It's a warm evening.
我们其中一辆马车轮子坏了
One of our wagons lost a wheel,
所以要回来找帮手
so we had to turn back here to get help.
有人告诉我...
One of the men tells me...
巴克斯特袭击了小屋
the Baxters attacked the small house.
你知道这件事吗？
Do you know about it?
告诉我你掌握的情况
Tell me what you know.
说
Well?
你把玛丽索尔藏哪了？
Where did you hide Marisol?
卢比奥
Rubio.
你口渴了 想喝水吗？
You are thirsty. You want to drink?
喝太急了 根本没喝到
No, no, it is too soon to drink.
把他带过来
Bring him over here!
你就像一个顽固的白痴
You're behaving like a stubborn idiot.
告诉我们玛丽索尔在哪
Tell us where Marisol is...
一切就了结了
and it will all be ended!
一个星期后你就康复了 想去哪就去哪
In a week, you'll be back in shape. You can go wherever you want.
今天到此为止
That's enough for today.
他迟早得开口 只是时间的问题
Sooner or later, he'll talk. It's just a matter of time.
注意别让他跑了或死了 其余你们看着办
Watch out he doesn't escape or die otherwise. Do what you like.
最好等他恢复知觉 他现在什么也感觉不到
And wait till he comes to. This way, he hardly feels anything.
我有个牌局等了三天了
I've had a poker hand waiting three days.
我现在却被困在这里看守这个美国白痴
Now I'm stuck here! I can't get to it while I'm guarding this americano idiot!
你会发觉这比打牌更好玩
I think you will find this more amusing than cards.
别把他搞死就行
All orders are to be sure he does not die...
但也要让他后悔投胎
and also make sure he regrets the day he was born.
那个外国佬睡着了
The gringo is asleep, I imagine.
没关系 我会享受叫醒他的
That's all right. I'll enjoy waking him up.
-伊斯特班 那是什么声音？-我不知道
-Esteban, what was that noise?  -I do not know.
我听到一声大叫 然后是撞击声
I heard a yell, and then a crash.
再躲也没用
It's useless to hide.
你耍不了小聪明了
You're finished playing the smart boy.
上阁楼看看
Go up and look in the loft.
酒桶后面也别放过
And take a look behind the barrels!
我们离开这里
Let's get out of here!
快！快点！
Hurry! Quick!
快点泼水 喂 你跟我来
Hurry with that water! Hey, you, come with me!
包围城镇 封锁所有街道出口
Surround the town! Block all the streets leading out!
给我找到他
Find him for me!
-伊斯特班 搜查全镇  -跟我来
-Esteban, search the whole town. -Follow me!
立刻把他找回来 不管什么代价
Get him back right now! You've got to at any cost!
看看马厩 看看所有畜栏和库房
Look in the stables, in every corral, in the stores!
还有教堂
Look for him in the church!
到那儿看看 不准放过任何角落
Go in there! Search every inch of it!
不要遗漏
Search everywhere!
卢比奥 进来
Rubio, in here!
哪户人匿藏他 就烧了他的房子
If somebody is hiding him, burn their house down...
像宰狗一样把他们宰了
and kill them like dogs!
你们 上那
You, up here!
在巴克斯特地界找找 要活捉
Look for him near the Baxters, but I want him alive!
活捉！
Alive!
卢比奥 去酒馆
Rubio, in the bar.
他说他什么都不知道 他在耍花样
He says he knows nothing. He's trying to be smart.
带到我这里来
Bring him here to me.
-我说的实话  -你什么都不知道 是吗？
-I'm telling the truth. -Well, you know nothing, huh?
-我没看见他 -卢比奥 你搞定他
-I'm not cheating. -Rubio, you take care of him.
你把他藏哪里了？
Where have you hidden him?
我没有藏匿他
I didn't hide him.
你跟那个卑劣的美国佬做朋友
You're the right friend for that filthy americano.
你的下场会跟他一样
You'll end up the same way.
我们找遍了所有地方
We looked everywhere.
地窖 阁楼 房顶
In his cellar, in the attic, on the roof.
但什么踪迹都没有
There is no trace.
后面房间也没人
I couldn't find anybody in the back room.
我想他肯定是向巴克斯特寻求庇护了
I'm certain he has taken refuge with the Baxters.
那个美国佬不蠢 他知道那边是最好的藏身之地
The americano isn't stupid. He knows that's the best place to hide.
巴克斯特家族？
The Baxters, eh?
最好去抓住他
Then better go and get him.
这是做他朋友的下场
And that's for being his friend.
天杀的
Curse them.
皮里佩洛
Piripero?
-过来  -我没看到人
-Come here. -I can't see anybody.
这里
Come here.
你在里面干什么？
What are you doing in there?
别管了 帮我离开这里
Never mind. Get me out of here.
但你还没死呢
But you're not dead yet.
不帮我离开这里 我就会死 快
I will be if you don't get me out of here, quick.
把盖放下
Get that lid down.
卢比奥！
Rubio!
还有人活着
I see some signs of life.
准备好 他们会随时出来
Let's be ready when they decide to come out.
不要开枪 我们投降
Don't shoot! We surrender!
住手！别开枪！我们出来！
Stop! Don't shoot! We're coming out!
-我投降！别开枪!  -别开枪！
-I surrender! Hold back your fire! -Don't shoot!
我们投降
We surrender!
住手
Stop.
我想见证这一幕
I wanna take a look at this.
雷蒙 别开枪！我们就出来
Ramon, don't shoot! We're coming out!
我们投降
We surrender!
听着 你们赢了 够了
Listen, you've won. It's enough!
我会离开小镇 你要我怎样做都行
I'll get out of town! I'll do whatever you like!
-你保证？-我发誓 雷蒙
-You promise that?  -I swear it! Ramon.
你不会又耍什么花样吧？
You won't try a trick of any kind?
绝不会 不耍花样
None! No, no tricks!
我说过了 我保证我们会离开的
I said before, I give you my word. We'll leave!
你确定吗？你最好先征求你太太的同意
Are you sure? You had better ask permission of your wife.
也许她不太乐意
Maybe she won't be too happy!
安东尼奥！
Antonio!
约翰！
John!
凶手
Murderers.
他们没有持枪
They had no guns.
凶手！你们下地狱去吧
Murderers! I hope you rot in hell!
你们兄弟将血债血偿！我诅咒你们！
May you and your brothers die spitting blood! Curse you for this!
凶手！
Murderers!
我们走 好戏已经结束了
Let's go. The show's over anyway.
继续找他 在尸堆里找
Keep looking for him. Search among those bodies.
那个美国佬肯定在某个地方
The filthy americano has to be somewhere!
西尔瓦尼托？
Silvanito?
西尔瓦尼托在哪儿？
Where's Silvanito?
今天有什么消息吗？
Any news today?
我得告诉你一些坏消息
I have to tell you some news that's pretty bad.
我不想告诉你这些 但...
-I hate to tell you this, Joe, but...
西尔瓦尼托呢？
Where is Silvanito?
西尔瓦尼托？他今早被拉蒙的人抓住了
Silvanito? He was captured this morning by those men of Ramon's.
他们在镇外抓住他的 他当时正往矿洞这边走
They grabbed him outside the village. He was on his way to this mine.
他本来要带一些补给品来 现在却被雷蒙抓走了
He was bringing in some provisions. Ramon's got him now.
他被严刑拷打 但他不会说的
He's being tortured, but he won't talk.
我很了解他 他是顽强的人
I know him well. He's a stubborn man.
不管他们怎样折磨他 就算丢了命他也不会说的
No matter what they do, he won't say a word, even if it means his life.
相信我 他们绝不可能逼他就范的
Listen to me. They'll never be able to force him.
你这老顽固 快开口说吧
Now, fool, loosen up your tongue.
-休想 -卢比奥！
-No! -Rubio!
你最好回你的店里去 老头
You better get back to your shop, old man.
-你就快有生意上门了  -啊 太好了
-You're liable to have some business. -Ah, very good!
我就想听这句话
That's what I wanted to hear.
我还为你带来了一份小惊喜
And I have a little surprise for you that I brought along.
我知道你很需要它
I know how much you'll need it.
我费了很大的劲才弄到手的
It was very hard to get my hands on.
我第一次动脑筋 没有人能抗拒两桶酒的
I got it by first using my head. No one can resist two barrels of wine.
对吗？然后我想...
Isn't that right? Then I thought that...
你可能需要那把枪 我还带来了另一份礼物
well, you might need that pistol, and I brought another present.
炸药 我从罗霍家族偷来的
It's dynamite. I stole it from the Rojos.
我看现在是你点燃导火线的时机了
And now it seems to me the moment's come for you to light the fuse...
把炸药送回给他们
and send it back to them.
天还挺亮
Still lots of light.
现在睡觉还太早了
Too early to be asleep yet.
卢比奥 枪给我
Rubio, here.
我不想糟蹋这把来复枪 再也找不到一把这么好的了
I shouldn't like to ruin the rifle. I could never find another like this.
听着 雷蒙 我们来试试这个
Listen, Ramon, let's try it with this one now.
外国佬！
Gringo!
听说你想见我
Heard you wanted to see me.
美国佬死定了
The americano's dead.
把那位老人家放下来
Let the old man down.
怎么了 雷蒙？
What's wrong, Ramon?
怎么没打到呢？
You losing your touch?
你在害怕吗 雷蒙？
Are you afraid, Ramon?
"想杀人时 一定得瞄准心脏"
"You shoot to kill, you better hit the heart."
你自己说的 雷蒙
Your own words. Ramon.
心脏 雷蒙
The heart. Ramon.
别忘记瞄准心脏
Don't forget the heart.
瞄准心脏 否则你是无法阻止我的
Aim for the heart or you'll never stop me.
当手持点45手枪的人  对决手持来福枪的人
When a man with a.45 meets a man with a rifle...
你说拿手枪的人必死无疑
You said the man with the pistol's a dead man.
我们看看是不是真的
Let's see if that's true.
动手啊 子弹上膛开枪吧
Go ahead, load up and shoot.
喂 听着 乔
Hey, listen, Joe.
听着 我...
Listen, l-l...
我想你们政府会很高兴拿回黄金的
Well, guess your government will be glad to see that gold back.
你呢
And you,
你不想留在这里等他们来吧？
you don't want to be here when they get it, eh?
你是说墨西哥政府在一边
You mean the Mexican government on one side...
美国政府在另一边？
and maybe the Americans on the other side?
我 就在中间？
Me, right smack in the middle?
嗯 太危险了
Mm-mmm. Too dangerous.
再见了
So long.
再见
Adios.